<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tingting&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tingting&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data manipulation in R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-07-data_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-07-data_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Aggregation library(magrittr) set.seed(1) ex_dat &amp;lt;- data.frame(group = rep(1:3, each = 2), y = rnorm(6), x = rnorm(6)) ex_dat ## group y x ## 1 1 -0.6264538 0.4874291 ## 2 1 0.1836433 0.7383247 ## 3 2 -0.8356286 0.5757814 ## 4 2 1.5952808 -0.3053884 ## 5 3 0.3295078 1.5117812 ## 6 3 -0.8204684 0.3898432 Summarise selected columns by group
dplyr::group_by(ex_dat, group) %&amp;gt;% dplyr::summarise(total_y = sum(y)) ## # A tibble: 3 x 2 ## group total_y ## &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; ## 1 1 -0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL notes</title>
      <link>/post/sql-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sql-notes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Structured Query Language (SQL) is a standard computer language for relational database management and data manipulation. It can be used to read, write, and update data. For data scientists, it is mainly used for data retrieval. There are several relational database management systems, such as Oracle, MySQL, and SQLite. Depending on the system you are using, the SQL syntax may be a little bit different.
Retrieve data Use SELECT statement to query database, filtered by some conditions (optional).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala notes III -- Classes and Objects</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-25-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-25-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Classes and objects In Scala, a class is a blueprint for objects. Once you define a class, you can create objects from the class blueprint with the keyword new. Through the object you can use all functionalities of the defined class.
An object is a named instance with members such as fields and methods. It is a class that has exactly one instance. There are three uses of objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala notes II -- Functions</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-26-scala2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-26-scala2/</guid>
      <description>Function Syntax Scala is a functional programming language, which means that functions are first-class citizens and you can pass them around as parameters or values.
def add(x: Int, y: Int): Int = { return x + y; } println(add(21, 19)); // Other variants def multiply(x: Int, y: Int): Int = x * y // simplified version def divide(x: Int, y: Int) = x / y // can ignore the output type if it&amp;#39;s obvious def substract(x: Int = 10, y: Int = 2) = x - y // set default values You can define the function names as operator, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala notes I</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-18-scala1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-18-scala1/</guid>
      <description>Data types Boolean true or false Byte 8 bit signed value Short 16 bit signed value Char 16 bit unsigned Unicode character Int 32 bit signed value Long 64 bit signed value Float 32 bit IEEE 754 single-precision float Double 64 bit IEEE 754 double-precision float String A sequence of characters Unit Corresponds to no value Null null or empty references Nothing subtype of every other type; includes no .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git commands</title>
      <link>/post/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Set up global configuration variables if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so
$ git config --global user.name &amp;quot;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&amp;quot; $ git config --global user.email &amp;quot;&amp;lt;email&amp;gt;&amp;quot;  Git should automatically do a rebase when you do a pull, which is what you want
$ git config branch.autosetuprebase always  To set up configuration for DiffMerge, follow the guide http://coding4streetcred.com/blog/post/configure-diffmerge-for-your-git-difftool.
Local Usage of Git Staging Check if there is any unstaged or untracked files</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr (Spark in R)</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-10-sparklyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-10-sparklyr/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The R programming language, along with RStudio, has become one of the most popular tools for data analysis as it contains a large amount of open-source packages developed by a community of statisticians. However, R or RStudio is not ideal for Big Data analysis as mostly the data would not fit into R memory. On the other hand, Spark has become the leading platform for big-data analytics. It works with the system to distribute data across clusters and process data in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-03-arima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-03-arima/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The ARIMA (autoregressive integrated moving average) models are also known as Box–Jenkins models. ARIMA models are applied in some cases where data show evidence of non-stationarity, where an initial differencing step (corresponding to the “integrated” part of the model) can be applied one or more times to eliminate the non-stationarity.
The AR part of ARIMA indicates that the evolving variable of interest is regressed on its own lagged (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Time-Series Models</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-21-bsts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-21-bsts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction State-space models were originally developed by control engineers, particularly for applications that require continuous updating of the current position. An example, from the field of navigation systems, is updating an user equipment’s position. The models have also found increasing use in many types of time-series problems, including parameter estimation, smoothing, and prediction. Structural time-series models are state-space models for time-series data. They are useful in practice because they are</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>