<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tingting&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tingting&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git commands</title>
      <link>/post/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Set up global configuration variables if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so
$ git config --global user.name &amp;quot;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&amp;quot; $ git config --global user.email &amp;quot;&amp;lt;email&amp;gt;&amp;quot;  Git should automatically do a rebase when you do a pull, which is what you want
$ git config branch.autosetuprebase always  To set up configuration for DiffMerge, follow the guide http://coding4streetcred.com/blog/post/configure-diffmerge-for-your-git-difftool.
Local Usage of Git Staging Check if there is any unstaged or untracked files</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr (Spark in R)</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-10-sparklyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-10-sparklyr/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe R programming language, along with RStudio, has become one of the most popular tools for data analysis as it contains a large amount of open-source packages developed by a community of statisticians. However, R or RStudio is not ideal for Big Data analysis as mostly the data would not fit into R memory. On the other hand, Spark has become the leading platform for big-data analytics. It works with the system to distribute data across clusters and process data in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-03-arima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-03-arima/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe ARIMA (autoregressive integrated moving average) models are also known as Box–Jenkins models. ARIMA models are applied in some cases where data show evidence of non-stationarity, where an initial differencing step (corresponding to the “integrated” part of the model) can be applied one or more times to eliminate the non-stationarity.
The AR part of ARIMA indicates that the evolving variable of interest is regressed on its own lagged (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Time-Series Models</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-21-bsts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-21-bsts/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionState-space models were originally developed by control engineers, particularly for applications that require continuous updating of the current position. An example, from the field of navigation systems, is updating an user equipment’s position. The models have also found increasing use in many types of time-series problems, including parameter estimation, smoothing, and prediction. Structural time-series models are state-space models for time-series data. They are useful in practice because they are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-16-git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-16-git-commands/</guid>
      <description>Git commandscode{white-space: pre;}pre:not([class]) {background-color: white;}if (window.hljs) {hljs.configure({languages: []});hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad();if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) {window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0);}}h1 {font-size: 34px;}h1.title {font-size: 38px;}h2 {font-size: 30px;}h3 {font-size: 24px;}h4 {font-size: 18px;}h5 {font-size: 16px;}h6 {font-size: 12px;}.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>